CARLA SEVERE

WEB DEVELOPER

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

HTML5 CSS3
JavaScript jQuery
Bootstrap3 Sass
React Redux
Node.js Express
MySQL Python

EDUCATION

BA ENGLISH & BIOLOGY Tuft University | 2005 - 2009

MA SOCIOLOGY & EDUCATION
Columbia University | 2009 - 2011

CONTACT

P: 404-618-8049

E: carla.severe@gmail.com

ONLINE

WEBSITE: http://css.carlasevere.com/css-portfolio/src/

LINKEDIN: linkedin.com/in/carla-

GITHUB: github.com/csevere

TWITTER: twitter.com/Carla Severe

ABOUT

Transitioning into the passionate life of a web developer. Desires to use programming skills, along with talents in writing and research, to bring long-term, uplifting transformation to people's lives. Never stops learning. Always striving for growth and uniqueness.

FEATURED PROJECTS

WRITEIT

August 2017

- Repo: https://github.com/csevere/writeIt-react-express
- WriteIT is a productivity tool for writers, offering a variety
 of ways to organize, structure, and plan manuscripts. It also
 incorporates a social networking feature that allows writers
 to share their work and receive or give feedback; aka,
 facebook for writers.

ALIEN BATTLECRAFT

July 2017

- Site: http://alienbattlecraft.carlasevere.com/alien-game/
- Repo: https://github.com/csevere/alien-game
- An interactive dice game in which players must fight aliens that have invaded their spacecraft. Winning requires some strategy and good luck.

WORK EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPER STUDENT

DigitalCrafts | Apr 2017 - Aug 2017

- 16-week immersive, full-time learning program
- Covering full stack web development: Python, JavaScript, including Node.js, MySQL, Express, HTML/CSS, and Amazon Web Services

ESL INSTRUCTOR

Boston, Japan, Korea | Sep 2011 - Sep 2016

- Recognized for the ability to develop, improve, and implement curricula that significantly increased students' participation, enthusiasm, and learning skills.
- Achieved 90-95% satisfaction score in student evaluations.